<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:atom='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<channel>
<atom:link href='http://make.webrage.co.nz/' rel='self' type='application/rss+xml'/>
<title>
make
</title>
<link>
http://make.webrage.co.nz/
</link>
<description>
make.webrage
</description>
<lastBuildDate>
Sat, 08 Sep 2018 17:10:04 +1200
</lastBuildDate>
<generator>
clj-rss
</generator>
<item>
<guid>
http://make.webrage.co.nz/posts/2018-09-03-first-post/
</guid>
<link>
http://make.webrage.co.nz/posts/2018-09-03-first-post/
</link>
<title>
Hello world
</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I have been wanting to play with &lt;a href='http://cryogenweb.org'&gt;Cryogen&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. It is a clojure based helper for creating static web sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having had a quick look at it I decided to go with the lotus theme by &lt;a href='https://github.com/KingMob'&gt;KingMob&lt;/a&gt;. It has a simple and uncluttered look that I like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;setup&amp;#95;issues&quot;&gt;setup issues&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With any new process there is stuff to learn and figure out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;cryogen&quot;&gt;cryogen&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being familiar with clojure I was quickly able to bring the getting started website to life at localhost. I use the &lt;a href='https://ide.atom.io/'&gt;Atom IDE&lt;/a&gt; for occasional clojure programming, so Cryogen and Atom were a good fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The development process involves running a ring server from the project directory.  This enables Cryogen to generate a new version of the website (in the IDE, and in the browser) every time the file that you are working on is saved. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;lotus&amp;#95;theme&quot;&gt;lotus theme&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fun began when I decided to go with the lotus theme and the website wouldn't render in the browser. This theme uses &lt;a href='https://sass-lang.com/'&gt;SASS&lt;/a&gt; for its style sheets, so I had to install the SASS command-line app and update the config file.  I was happy to install this as it looks interesting. Still no luck. Turns out the latest version of the SASS command-line app doesn't work the same as previously, leaving Cryogen throwing an error when it called SASS.  My current work-around is to manually call SASS to parse the theme scss files into css files (into the same directory).  This is only needed after a scss file is updated, which shouldn't be too often. This work around will do until Cryogen and SASS are back in sync.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;github&quot;&gt;github&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next challenge was to store the website on &lt;a href='https://github.com/'&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.  Not hard, just that I hadn't done it before.  Turns out Atom, the IDE I use, makes the process pretty easy once you get the settings right. I just wanted to save the bare bones website to github without any extraneous file / folder clutter. It took a bit of playing around, but not too long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;netlify&quot;&gt;netlify&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be good to give &lt;a href='http://netlify.com'&gt;netlify&lt;/a&gt; a go. It offers free hosting for static web sites. Netlify can grab any updates to the github website repository and update the website from there. The most important change I had to make was to ensure there was no blog prefix in the Cryogen config file, otherwise the relative paths in the website were wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;the&amp;#95;final&amp;#95;process&quot;&gt;the final process&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;To create a new post on my website, the steps are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fire up the Atom IDE and open up the cryogen website code&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If I change one of the scss style sheet files, run a script to create associated css files&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run a ring server so I can check the changes as I save them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use markdown to write a post or page, saving occasionally to check it looks OK&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In Atom, push the committed changes to github&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wait a minute or two and check the website is all OK&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
<pubDate>
Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +1200
</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
